Guide to the George Starkovich Ephemera Collection
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- George Starkovich collection of sociopolitical pamphlets and papers, 1935-1957; 0305-001; 4.44 cubic feet 23 boxes
  - Pamphlets and Small Publications, Series 2
    - Treason In Congress: The Record of the Un-American Activities Committee; Albert E. Kahn ;Literature Division of the Progressive Citizens of America, Undated (Box 22)
    - The Time of the Toad; Dalton Trumbo; The Hollywood Ten, October, 1949 (Box 22)
    - The McCarran Conspiracy; Communist Party, USA, April, 1951 (Box 23)
    - The Walter-McCarran Law; Introduction by Abner Green; American Committee For the Protection of Foreign Born, 1953 (Box 23)
    - Hey, Brother...There's a Law Against You!; The National Committee to Defeat the Mundt Bill, Undated (Box 23)
    - In Defense of the Right to Defend Foreign Born Americans; Abner Green; American Committee For the Protection of Foreign Born, 1955 (Box 23)
    - Our Generation Will Not Be Silent!; Labor Youth League, September, 1953 (Box 23)
    - Let the People Know Eugene Dennis; New Century Publishers, April, 1947 (Box 23)
    - The Trade Unions and the War; William Z. Foster; International Publishers, June, 1942 (Box 23)
    - McCarthy On Trial; Albert E. Kahn Cameron & Kahn Inc., 1952 (Box 23)
    - Some Problems of Work in Right-Led Unions; John Swift; New Century Publishers, June, 1952 (Box 23)
    - Two Conventions of Labor: The Situation in the Trade Union Movement; John Williamson; New Century Publishers, January, 1949 (Box 23)
    - Who's un-American!; C. W. Fowler; issued by Food, Tobacco, Agricultural and Allied Workers Union of America, July, 1947 (Box 23)
    - The Work of the Soviet Trade Unions in the Field of Social Insurance of the Workers; A. Gorbunov; The Publishing House of the All-Union Central Council of Trade Unions, 1945 (Box 23)
    - If This Be Treason; Richard O. Boyer; New Century Publishers, December, 1948 (Box 23)
    - McCarthyism and the Big Lie; Milton Howard; New Century Publishers, November, 1953 (Box 23)
    - A Policy for Labour; Harry Pollitt; Communist Party, Undated (Box 23)
    - Tasks of the Trade Union for Economic and Social Development and in the Struggle for National Independence and Democratic Liberties in the Capitalist and Colonial Countries; Giuseppe Di Vittorio; W.F.T.U Publications Ltd, October, 1953 (Box 23)
    - Reply on Behalf of World Fellowship; Royal Wilbur France; The Hecla Press, Undated (Box 23)
    - The Rights You Save May be Your Own; Simon W. Gerson; New Century Publishers, Undated (Box 23)
    - Can Americans Tolerate Prison for Ideas?; The National Committee to Win Amnesty for the Smith act Prisoners, April, 1954 (Box 23)
    - Our Country Right or Wrong; Technocracy Inc., October, 1946 (Box 23)
    - The Red-Baiters Menace America; Eugene Dennis; New Century Publishers, October, 1946 (Box 23)
    - Working Agreement (Plywood and Veneer Workers Union Local No.); affiliated with the Congress of Industrial Affairs, Undated (Box 23)
    - Constitution and By-Laws (Plywood, Box Shook and Door Council District No. 9--IWA-CIO) Plywood Box Shook & Door Council Dist. No. 9, Undated (Box 23)
    - Working Agreement (between Bellingham Plywood Corporation and Plywood and Veneer Workers Union Local No. 330); Affiliated with the Congress of Industrial Affairs, Undated (Box 23)
    - Agreement ;Bethlehem Steel Company, Bethlehem Pacific Coast Steel Corporation, Buffalo Tank Corporation, August, 1952 (Box 23)
    - Constitution of the American Federation of Labour; American Federation of Labor, 1942 (Box 23)
    - By-Laws of Lumber and Sawmill Workers Union; Affiliated with United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, February, 1950 (Box 23)
    - Constitution and By-Laws; Affiliated with CIO, (Plywood and Veneer Workers' Union Local No. 9.330), Undated (Box 23)
    - By-Laws; United Steelworkers of America - Seattle, WA, October, 1949 (Box 23)
    - Constitution of the International Union; United Mine Workers of America Washington DC, November, 1948 (Box 23)
    - Constitution of International Union; United Steelworkers of America CIO - Atlantic City, NJ, September, 1954 (Box 23)
    - "This Rugged Shore You Loved..."; Minnesota Labor, Undated (Box 23)
    - Constitution of the Communist Party of the United States of America; Communist Party, USA, 1948 (Box 23)
    - The Communist Party of the Soviet Union: Syllabus for Six Lessons on The history of the C.P.S.U; Communist Party, USA, 1949 (Box 23)
    - Dialectical and Historical Materialism; Communist Party, USA, 1948 (Box 23)
    - The Deportation Terror: A Weapon to Gag America; Abner Green; New Century Publishers, 1950 (Box 23)
    - The People and the Congress; William Z. Foster; International Publishers, 1943 (Box 23)
    - The Big Plot: Proof of the Justice Department's Plan to Jail 21,105 Americans; National Nonpartisan Committee, Approximately 1951 (Box 23)
    - The Present Situation and the Next Tasks; William Z. Foster; New Century Publishers, 1945 (Box 23)
    - Is Dewey The Man?; Sender Garlin; International Publishers, September, 1945 (Box 23)
    - Jungle Law or Human Reasons: The North Atlantic Pact and What it Means to You; Jessica Smith; SRT Publications Inc., 1949 (Box 23)
- George Starkovich materials regarding the WTO 1999 Seattle Ministerial Conference protests, 1999-2000; 0305-002; .21 cubic ft (1 legal size document case)
  Flyers, newsletters, meeting agendas, and newsclippings relating to George Starkovich's role as a planner and participant in the 1999 World Trade Organization Seattle Ministerial Conference protests.
  Open to all users.
  Received 2014-12-14